I left the village when I was thirteen .
I became a leading actor at sixteen .
I was once very successful .
But if you ask me again , I did it all just to get by .
I never imagined I would end up in this shit hole
at this point in my life .
Many people say the film world is ridiculous .
However , life is even more ridiculous .
I once said , if I lose my memory one day .
Someone will have to teach me how to smile again .
Smiling is tiring .
I 'm very tired .
And I don 't want to go on .
Hey , let me help you .
I was having lunch , and completely lost track of time .
You 're the one they call Uncle Yin ?
Well , most of the time they just call me Gramps .
But those who have been here for a while call me ' Uncle Yin ' .
It 's just a name . It 's whatever .
Uncle Yin , are you the only security guard here ?
There 's no one but me .
I know everyone and everybody here . Family backgrounds ,
even when they take out the trash and stuff .
It 's a safe neighborhood , don 't you worry .
Come on in .
It 's not too bad in here .
No one 's lived here for a while .
It just needs to be tidied up and it will be as good as new .
Uncle Yin .
What is this ? That 's really not necessary .
Please take it .
It will be .
I only opened the door for you . I was just doing my job .
You 're too kind .
Most people leave this place and move up , never the other way around .
But I 've never seen someone famous move in here .
Well , since you are moving into a new place ...
it is important to perform the rituals .
You know , just to say hi .
Put your stuff down ...
Here , take this . It 's just a polite gesture .
Shall we ?
Calm down now ...
Nothing crazy , alright ? Show respect .
Don 't do anything crazy now .
With respect ...
I 'll leave you alone now .
What time is it , Mr. Fox ?
It 's twelve now Daddy .
Mommy wants me to go to sleep .
When are you coming back ?
Today , she made me wash off the watch you drew .
I haven 't seen you for days ...
When are you coming back to draw me another one ?
Don 't forget your blanket .
Lights out
who are you talking to ?
Hear my prayer ... do no evil ... get out you devils ...
Everything 's alright now .
Let him be . He needs to be alone .
Let 's go .
Get some rest then .
Off you go , everyone ...
Everything 's good now .
You should all go home and get ready for dinner .
What time is it , Mr. Fox ?
It 's twelve now Daddy .
Mommy wants me to go to sleep .
When are you coming back ?
Today , she made me wash off the watch you drew .
When are you coming back to draw me another one ?
Don 't forget your blanket .
Lights out ...
Pardon me , pardon me ... Good luck to you ...
You don 't have to thank me .
I 'm sorry for eating your chicken .
I 'm sorry ... I 'm sorry ...
I 'm sorry , I 'm sorry ...
I beg your pardon , sorry to be a bother ...
Good luck to you ... you need to watch out for yourself ...
He 's been here for an hour nursing that one beer .
He 's probably waiting for you .
Why are you so late ?
It 's going to be busy as hell in a minute .
So ? We never have that much customers anyways .
I know exactly who sits where and who orders what .
Ping always has the steamed meat with preserved vegetables
and a double order of the house special glutinous rice .
Old Chung and Jill have the stir fried fish with noodles ,
vegetables , and some of our rice with extra oil .
Wing Ping will have the steamed fish with scallions , less oil ,
and some pork with a double order of glutinous rice .
Yung , Keung and Kit always have the Soup of the Day along with our rice ,
and salty fish with vegetables to eat here .
Auntie Lai , a bowl of white rice with the Soup of the Day ; but to go .
Auntie Lai passed away last month .
So ? She still needs to eat , doesn 't she ?
We prepare exactly 28 bowls of glutinous rice every day .
Who is this order for ?
I 'll cook these myself . On the house .
If it wasn 't for Brother Yau 's generosity ,
you would be charged double for that !
House special kale and fried ribs .
Two bowls of congee ! Split two ways .
Auntie Mui .
Wait a minute . I 'll be right there .
Auntie Lai , you should be on your way now after you have had a good meal .
You should eat while it 's hot .
Why do you have your food split two ways ?
I have diabetes ,
and I can 't eat salt . Doctor 's orders .
Yau is very kind .
He makes two portions for me .
One half is regular . The other is low sodium .
So it 's good for both my husband and I.
- Is the steamed rice ready ? - Fuck off .
He 's not as kind as Auntie Mui though . She 's an angel .
She helps out by sewing everyone 's clothes .
She takes care of the kids in the building .
Cooks and helps with groceries too .
Listen to all those sweet words . What is it you need this time ?
Can you alter the waist a bit ?
Yes , of course .
But please don 't let Uncle Tung know .
Last time he found out , he was telling me off the whole way home .
Have to get back to work . I don 't want to piss my boss off .
Are you good with sewing ?
Not really .
I have nothing else to do . So ...
I look for something to do .
Just trying to help where I can .
Do you have clothes that need repairing ?
Well ...
I have some old film costumes
from my movies .
I 've kept them for years .
It 's a pity how damaged they have become over the years .
I can help you ...
so you can keep them in better condition .
So ... how long are you planning to stay here ?
Why do you ask ?
Nothing really .
I 'm sorry for being nosy .
Have you noticed anything
in apartment 2442 ?
It 's been vacant for so long .
You know what I mean , don 't you ?
I don 't believe in those things .
It 's probably for the best you don 't .
Is this meant to be worn by humans ?
Why does a pig need to wear clothes ?
Stop moving or I 'll prick you !
Have you seen those pig feet of hers ? She 's so fucking fat .
Just you wait and see . Yau 's place is going to close down .
That fat pig eats everything !
Gosh ... that mouth of yours !
You know what I think . It 's a conspiracy .
Yau and that fat pig want us to end up fatter than her !
Her squinty little pig eyes .
Old man , they don 't charge us for it , you know .
That 's the point ! Free food and large portions .
How is that not a conspiracy ?
I 'm telling you .
Someday , I 'm going to kill them with a fucking nuclear bomb .
Ouch ! That hurts !
Fucking parents , letting their kids out at this time of the night .
Your glutinous rice is amazing .
So , where does that get me ?
You make the best in town .
What more do you want ?
My great-great grandfather started carrying glutinous rice ,
with him way back in the old days .
You probably know that it 's not just used for cooking , right ?
What else ? For hunting Vampires ?
Oh ? So you know that Vampires are afraid of glutinous rice ? Eh ?
In the old days , all successful Vampire Hunters ,
had special relationships with the best rice shops .
They get discounts for the glutinous rice they needed .
Rice was really worth something back then .
Vampire hunters carried glutinous rice with them at all times .
This relationship was passed down from generation to generation .
And subsequently to me .
All the Vampires have miraculously vanished ,
along with all the Vampire hunters .
So what do Vampire Hunters do when there are no fucking Vampires left ?
They cook .
Thank you for saving my life this morning .
You mean getting in your way ?
But just because I stopped you once ,
doesn 't mean I can stop you the next time .
Save it and thank me if you 're still around next time .
Old man , where have you been ?
It 's late .
I was looking for you .
I was here .
I was afraid of losing you .
Why are your feet still so cold ? Soaking isn 't helping ?
Are you not feeling well ?
I 'm alright .
I 'll be back in a few days .
Wait for me .
Master , I 'll leave it to you then .
Don 't worry . I will take care of it .
This is a token of my appreciation . Please accept it .
I 'll be on my way now .
Gau .
Let 's talk privately .
Auntie Mui , that 's a lot of groceries .
Yes . Tung ... Tung is coming home .
He loves fish .
How is he ?
He 's good . He is coming home .
I should get back to work now .
Auntie Mui .
Pak .
You can 't come here anymore . Run along now . Be a good boy .
To preserve the body we must choose a dark place ,
within the place where he was last living .
In order to be discreet .
We bury his body in soil in the bathtub .
Later , we move the body into a coffin , in total darkness ,
suspended off the ground .
We will use crows ' blood instead of chicken blood ,
which will work with the amulet on his chest ,
collecting the essence of his " yin " spirit .
Clouds of the spirits ... open ... against the gods ' will ...
Remember , never take the mask off .
How much longer until Tung comes back ?
In seven days ,
Tung 's spirit will come back .
It may be the perfect time then .
May be ?
What if it doesn 't work ?
If it doesn 't work , there 's another way .
What is it ?
It 's very extreme . A last resort .
We will talk later .
Clouds of the spirits ... open ...
blessed by the ashes ...
spirits ... grant me the power ... against the gods ' will ...
Mommy !
The roast pork is nice .
They are gone now . They won 't come back .
Just walk against the wall at this hour every night .
Good luck to you . Good luck to you . Good luck to you .
Honey , The dying plant you brought home last week ,
it blossomed last night .
Please don 't misunderstand .
I 'm seventy-two .
If I weren 't looking after the two of them ,
I would have retired long ago .
I didn 't want them sent away !
They 've been asked to leave many times ...
So I found them a place to stay .
Why is that woman hanging around all the time ?
She lived in 2442 for years .
She was reserved and didn 't speak much .
She had a warm smile .
Her husband seemed like a nice man .
He was a tutor to two twin girls in the neighborhood .
Feng goes back to 2442 every day .
She gets scared , then leaves , and returns the next day .
She doesn 't dare to go inside , but she can 't stop herself from going back .
Her kid is a good boy .
She gathers the food offerings her neighbors leave outside their doors .
He just gobbles it all up without a word .
Is the bike yours ?
How about I fix it for you ?
Dear , you don 't like the food ?
You haven 't touched your plate at all .
It 's been getting windy lately .
It 's harder for me to go up and down the stairs .
Maybe I gained weight .
Maybe I did .
Maybe it 's a conspiracy .
Yau ... and that fat pig .
It 's a big conspiracy .
Yes it is , yes it is ...
Gosh , that mouth of yours !
Dear , we are not young anymore .
We will be a hundred years old sooner or later .
If you get cold , you have to bundle up .
Take care of yourself .
If you 're not happy , you have to speak up .
Don 't keep it inside , okay ?
The flowers are all dried out .
You told me not to climb up and down for them .
I can 't do it all on my own .
There are only two of us left , you know ?
Did I prick you ? You have to tell me if I did .
Please don 't leave me alone .
You said you would come back .
Why aren 't you eating ? You don 't like the food ?
You shouldn 't smoke too much .
I need to get one more pair of chopsticks . Take a seat .
You expecting company ?
Nah , just my flat mates .
You can see them ?
Sometimes .
And you still stay here ?
Do you think they are all haunted ?
They are attached to the land itself , not to the house .
I have stayed here for decades ,
but they have been here for centuries .
I will probably be living here when I die .
It makes sense to develop a good relationship beforehand .
I need your help .
It 's about apartment 2442 .
Do you think any museum will want this stuff ?
Should I sell them to one of those places that collects scrap metal ?
Are these things from your father ?
Yes , from many generations .
The brown stains , that 's blood .
It 's so deep that it can 't be washed away , No matter how hard I tried .
Back in the days , there were a lot of eerie things in my village .
We took care of them with these tools .
Where is your family now ?
In this business , no one gets a happy end .
Five hours , Five Hours ...
I will return before midnight .
Five Hours .
Four hours ?
I just remembered my father would leave me at our neighbor 's place ,
whenever he went to work .
Being a Taoist monk , he really didn 't earn much .
The money he earned wasn 't even enough to pay the babysitting fees .
Thanks .
For many generations ,
my family called wherever home .
But there was never a fucking home .
This was the last place my father brought me .
He planned for us to stay for a few days .
We ended up living here for decades .
How come ?
I will come back for you before midnight .
He went out one night and never came back .
After all , it 's all fate .
Pak drew this .
So what ?
I did all I could the last time .
If you are scared , that 's your problem . It 's not their fault .
Feng is mentally ill . She should go to a doctor .
After all , I 'm just a cook .
You can help , why don 't you ?
Why the hell is it your business ?
How do you know I can help ?
You don 't even know me .
Do you even fucking know them ?
Cut that shit , are you helping or not ?
Are you even capable of helping others ?
Look at yourself . You 're a fucking mess !
What 's that supposed to mean ?
That 's obviously drawn by a kid ,
The ink 's already faded and you 're still keeping it .
Couldn 't let it go , could you ?
If you really didn 't care ,
you wouldn 't bother keeping all these things , would you ?
In humans , there are both the good and the bad .
It is with spells as well .
The darker the color of the amulet paper ,
the greater the power of the spell .
To ask for power from the gods this way is evil .
It is an extreme measure
that endangers yourself and others .
Trust me , this is not that simple .
Thank you .
You son of a bitch !
You used his life as bait for the twins .
I 've asked for your help before ,
but you refused .
I didn 't have a choice .
I might as well have done it on my own .
You know how powerful those twins are .
You forced me to get involved .
At least it 's allover now .
You don 't look that great . You 're really pale .
Like you 're running out of time or something .
The cabinet can 't possibly hold them for much longer .
Burn it .
Let me take care of it .
Once I perform the ceremony .
I 'll burn it .
We have to stay like this forever .
Yes , forever .
When can we go home ?
As long as we are together ,
anywhere is our home .
Look , it 's still here .
Thank you .
Pak , stop playing and eat some food .
It won 't snow in Hong Kong , will it ?
No , I haven 't seen it .
So , will it ?
It may .
Mommy said , white is the most beautiful color in the world .
Is it ?
Yes .
Glutinous rice with vegetables !
What 's wrong with you people ? Prepping for a funeral ?
You all smell like menthol and eucalyptus oil .
We didn 't use any .
Iced lemon tea !
Iced lemon tea .
One iced lemon tea , coming right up !
Eat it while it 's hot . Okay .
Hey , did all of you get your clothes repaired by Mui ?
Yeah .
Has anyone seen Uncle Tung lately ?
Nope . How about you ask Uncle Yin ?
Feng told me that some guy killed Tung .
She said that the guy had a lot of kids with him .
Kids ? Here ?
Feng is nuts . You believe what she says ?
The railing on the stairwell is all bent and screwed up .
Look at this . I found
this tooth beside it .
What ? Is there a name on it ?
It looks like Tung 's gold teeth .
Every night at eleven ,
he opens his eyes .
His feet bang the top of the coffin .
As if he wants to jump .
Did you take off the mask ?
This is normal .
Don 't take off the mask .
Everything will be fine .
How much longer do I need to wait ?
Besides the growth of his hair and his nails ,
it doesn 't seem like anything is happening .
I 've been feeding him crows ' blood every day .
Should I get some blood from a black dog ?
The blood of black dogs is useless .
Trust me , just go home .
Gau , you said that there was another way .
What is it ? Please tell me .
What I need is the blood of a virgin .
Do you know how to get it ?
Don 't draw any attention to yourself ,
Tung will come back for sure .
Just remember , never ever take the mask off .
Uncle Yin , what do you want ?
Sorry to bother you , Gau .
I received some complaints .
Someone said there are kids making noises late at night .
I told them , it 's impossible . You don 't have kids .
It 's my responsibility to come by and check .
Well , thanks .
Auntie Mui !
What a surprise to see you .
I went to your place , but it 's been locked the past few days .
I thought you went back to your home town .
How is Tung ?
He 's fine . Thank you .
Really ?
Hey Gau .
I 've known you since you were a kid .
You 're still messing around with that black magic shit .
Where is Tung ?
Pak , are you going to Auntie Mui 's apartment ?
Hi there Auntie Mui . I haven 't seen you around lately .
Is everything okay ?
Everything 's fine .
Tung is unwell . I need to take care of him .
He 's just getting old . It 's nothing .
Take care of him .
Pak !
Don 't bother Uncle Tung !
It 's alright . He 's just a child .
Well , I 'm off then .
Auntie Mui , I need to pee .
You really want to go to the bathroom ?
Alright then .
I created it .
It started out as an accident .
You always warned me that my evil ways would be within me .
My final years has been unpleasant .
Terminal stage of lung cancer .
The cigarettes I smoke are made from ashes of the unborn .
Their yin for my yang . It 's the choice I 've made .
The smell coming out of Auntie Mui 's apartment ,
was from the preservatives .
You were in the process of turning Tung 's corpse into a vampire .
The twin ghosts
were needed to bring him back to life .
At eleven every night , you must scatter a packet of this onto his body .
This will get rid of the smell of rotting flesh .
I will come over tonight .
The twin ghosts are different from the unborn child .
Two lives as one . They are more potent .
I need a body that was big enough as a vessel
to hold them .
If we didn 't use the mask and the oil ,
Tung 's corpse would have been out of control .
I never thought it would turn out like this .
Iran out of time .
Pak !
Pak , where are you ?
Tung was the body without the spirit .
The twins were the spirits without the body .
I 'll prepare a trap in the hallway .
I 'll try to attract the vampire with the corpse oil .
Go find Feng .
Be quick !
Pak ...
The twins have possessed the vampire .
It happened so fast , they were gone blink of an eye .
Is there any way , you can help me fight ?
No ! If I do that , you 'll fucking die .
I should have died the first day I was here .
I still owe you my appreciation from that . We 're even now .
Let 's give it a try .
Let 's hope the corpse oil will attract the vampire .
Once you 're inside the trap , a cigarette is all the time you have .
Once it burns up ,
you 'll never be able to come back .
It 's all on you now .
WATER
WOOD
We 're running out of time !
Hurry the fuck up !
EARTH
METAL
FIRE
My dear Tung ,
let 's leave together .
Shall we ?
Trimming your toenails again ?
Get to work , you burn !
Would you like pork chops , sweetie ?
Help , somebody ! Help !
Dr. Choy , someone 's here to ID the body .
You are ... ?
I am his son .